Guide to the Montana Power Company Predecessor Company records 1880-1947
Montana Historical Society
- Missoula Public Service Company
  - Financial Records
    - Corporation license tax, 1928-1929 (Box-folder 135 / 5)
    - Dividing wall replacement expenses, 1927 (Box-folder 135 / 6)
    - Financial statements [continued from Missoula Light and Water Company subgroup], 1925-1927 (Box-folder 135 / 7-9)
    - Financial statements, 1928 (Box-folder 136 / 1)
    - General ledger index [Oversize Box], 1926-1928 (Oversizebox 11)
    - Financial statements: Bitter Root Valley System [continued from Missoula Light and Water Company subgroup], 1925-1928 (Box-folder 136 / 2-5)
    - General ledger, 1926-1928 (Volume 304)
    - General ledger: Bitter Root Valley System, 1927-1928 (Volume 305)
    - Insurance: automobile, 1925-1929 (Box-folder 136 / 6)
    - Insurance: employee life; surety, 1924-1927 (Box-folder 137 / 1)
    - Insurance: fire, 1925-1929 (Box-folder 137 / 2-3)
    - Inventories: Bitter Root Valley System, 1924-1928 (Box-folder 137 / 4-5)
    - Inventories: Light, Water, and Heating Depts., 1924-1928 (Box-folder 137 / 6-7)
    - Inventory: office, 1925 (Box-folder 137 / 8)
    - Journal / trial balances, 1926-1928 (Volume 306)
    - Sureties, 1925-1928 (Box-folder 137 / 9)
    - Tax assessments, 1927 (Box-folder 137 / 10)
    - Vouchers [scattered], 1925-1928 (Box-folder 137 / 11)
    - Voucher registers, 1924-1928 (Volume 307- 309)
    - Voucher register: Bitter Root Valley System, 1926-1929 (Volume 310)
    - Miscellaneous, 1925-1928 (Box-folder 137 / 12)
  - Legal Documents
    - Contracts: General Electric Company, 1925-1928 (Box-folder 138 / 1)
    - Contracts: City of Missoula, 1926-1929 (Box-folder 138 / 2)
    - Contracts: Missoula Federal Building, 1925-1929 (Box-folder 138 / 3)
    - Contracts: National Lamp Works (for Mazda Lamps), 1926-1927 (Box-folder 138 / 4)
    - Contracts: Northern Pacific Railway Company, 1929 (Box-folder 138 / 5)
    - Contracts: painters, 1925-1929 (Box-folder 138 / 6)
    - Contracts: pole line extensions, 1926-1928 (Box-folder 138 / 7)
    - Contracts: U.S. Forest Service (for protection of watershed of Rattlesnake Creek), 1925-1930 (Box-folder 138 / 8)
    - Contracts: Westinghouse Electric and Manufacturing Company, 1925-1927 (Box-folder 138 / 9)
    - Contracts: A-W, 1925-1929 (Box-folder 138 / 10-11)
    - Deeds, 1924 (Box-folder 138 / 12)
    - Leases, 1925-1928 (Box-folder 138 / 13)
  - Organizational Records
    - Miscellaneous (includes scattered minutes, annual report of corporation, proxies, offer to Missoula Light and Water Company), 1924-1929 (Box-folder 138 / 14)
  - Miscellany
    - Field books (includes hub leaks and Hamilton water waste survey), 1927-1928 (Box-folder 138 / 15)
- Missoula Street Railway Company
  - Court Papers
    - Clara B. Anderson vs. Missoula Street Railway Company, 1917 (Box-folder 139 / 1)
    - Awanda Kelley vs. Missoula Street Railway Company, 1915 (Box-folder 139 / 2)
    - Mary E. Pasley vs. Missoula Street Railway Company, 1912-1913 (Box-folder 139 / 3)
    - Harlan M. Townsend vs. Missoula Street Railway Company, 1922-1924 (Box-folder 139 / 4)
    - Daisy White vs. Missoula Street Railway Company, 1923-1924 (Box-folder 139 / 5)
    - J.E. Wilson vs. Missoula Street Railway Company, 1914 (Box-folder 139 / 6)
  - Employment Records
    - Applications for employment: A-W (includes address, age, date of birth, place of birth, nationality, next of kin, previous employment, surgeon's certificate of health, etc.), 1910-1927 (Box-folder 139 / 7-12)
    - Payroll: monthly and half-monthly (office workers and motormen), 1910-1912 (Box-folder 139 / 13-15)
    - Payroll: monthly and half-monthly (office workers and motormen), 1913-1926 (Box-folder 140 / 1-11)
    - Payroll: monthly and half-monthly (office workers and motormen), 1927-1928 (Box-folder 141 / 1-2)
    - Payroll: weekly (laborers and brakemen) [Oversize Box], 1909-1912 (Oversizebox 11)
    - Payroll: weekly (laborers and brakemen), 1913-1928 (Box-folder 141 / 3-13)
  - Financial Records
    - Cancelled checks (scattered), 1909-1910 (Box-folder 142 / 1)
    - Cash book, 1889-1897 (Box-folder 142 / 2)
    - Cash books, 1909-1928 (Volume 311- 312)
    - Cash ledger, 1889-1896 (Box-folder 142 / 3)
    - Corporate tax returns, 1909-1917 (Box-folder 142 / 4)
    - Financial statements, 1911-1914 (Box-folder 142 / 5-8)
    - Financial statements, 1915-1921 (Box-folder 143 / 1-7)
    - Financial statements, 1922-1927 (Box-folder 144 / 1-7)
    - General ledgers (includes Missoula Public Service Company Street Railway Dept.), 1909-1928 (Volume 313- 315)
    - Insurance: employee life, 1920-1926 (Box-folder 144 / 8)
    - Inventories, 1916-1928 (Box-folder 145 / 1-2)
    - Journal, 1889-1897 (Box-folder 145 / 3)
    - Journals / trial balances (includes Missoula Public Service Company Street Railway Dept.), 1909-1928 (Volume 316- 317)
    - Proof of solvency, 1922-1923 (Box-folder 145 / 4)
    - Rates and tariffs filed with Public Service Commission, 1919-1921 (Box-folder 145 / 5)
    - Trial balance, 1895 (Box-folder 145 / 6)
    - U.S. census return on electric railways, 1912 (Box-folder 145 / 7)
    - Voucher registers (includes Missoula Public Service Company Street Railway Dept.), 1909-1927 (Volume 318- 321)
    - Voucher register index, 1927 (Box-folder 145 / 8)
    - Work orders, 1912 (Box-folder 145 / 9)
    - Miscellaneous, 1910-1911, undated (Box-folder 145 / 10)
  - Hearings
    - Public Service Commission docket #478 Frank Beaulieu vs. Missoula Street Railway Company (re service on Bonner line), 1915 (Box-folder 145 / 11-12)
    - Public Service Commission docket #682 (re requested fair increase and rule change), 1918 (Box-folder 145 / 13)
  - Legal Documents
    - Contracts: Amalgamated Association of Street and Electric Railway Employees of America (motormen's union: includes threatened strike, May 1911), 1910-1923 (Box-folder 145 / 14)
    - Contracts: American Car Company (re building of first steet cars), 1910-1912 (Box-folder 145 / 15)
    - Contracts: Bonner Depot construction, 1911 (Box-folder 145 / 16)
    - Contracts: construction of system, 1909-1910 (Box-folder 146 / 1)
    - Contracts: General Electric Company, 1909-1924 (Box-folder 146 / 2)
    - Contracts: City of Missoula, 1912 (Box-folder 146 / 3)
    - Contracts: County of Missoula, 1908-1920 (Box-folder 146 / 4)
    - Contracts: G.H. Nash and Company (re Higgins Street bridge paving), 1914 (Box-folder 146 / 5)
    - Contracts: street car advertising, 1910, 1923-1924 (Box-folder 146 / 6)
    - Contracts: Westinghouse Electric and Manufacturing Company, 1909-1920 (Box-folder 146 / 7)
    - Contracts: Westinghouse Traction Brake Company, 1911-1925 (Box-folder 146 / 8)
    - Contracts: B-W, 1909-1922 (Box-folder 146 / 9)
    - Damage releases on building of lines, 1910-1911 (Box-folder 146 / 10)
    - Leases, 1910-1916 (Box-folder 146 / 11)
    - List of deeds, 1909-1925 (Box-folder 146 / 12)
    - Mortgages and releases, 1910-1925 (Box-folder 146 / 13)
    - Petitions for rail service, 1910-1911 (Box-folder 146 / 14)
  - Organizational Records
    - Annual reports of corporation, 1919-1924 (Box-folder 146 / 15)
    - Record book (includes minutes, annual statements, etc.), 1909-1918 (Volume 322)
    - Miscellaneous (includes articles of incorporation, proxies, dissolution), 1909-1925 (Box-folder 146 / 16)
  - Miscellany
    - Accident releases (scattered), 1910-1918 (Box-folder 146 / 17)
    - Accident reports, 1909-1917 (Box-folder 146 / 18-24)
    - Accident reports, 1920-1926 (Box-folder 147 / 1-8)
    - Field books: A-K, M-Q, S, 1910s (Box-folder 148 / 1-7)
    - Field books: T-Z, AA-DD, FF-KK, 1910s (Box-folder 149 / 1-6)
    - Heating Plant extension notebook, 1910s (Box-folder 149 / 7)
    - Instructions to motormen, 1911 (Box-folder 150 / 1)
    - Level books, 1910s (Box-folder 150 / 2)
    - Testimonial dinner for S.R. Inch, 1912 (Box-folder 150 / 3)
    - Transit books, 1910s (Box-folder 150 / 4-5)
- Missoula Water Works and Milling Company / Missoula Water Company
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - Letterpress book, 1886-1891 (Box-folder 151 / 1)
    - Letterpress copies [6 pages removed from otherwise empty book], 1898 (Box-folder 151 / 2)
    - Letterpress book [badly water damaged, only a few letters legible, some partially legible], circa 1900- 1901 (Box-folder 151 / 3)
  - Court Papers
    - Missoula Water Company vs. J.S. Kemp (re condemnation of land for reservoir), 1901 (Box-folder 151 / 4)
    - Missoula Water Company vs. Charles E. Williams (re L.E. Tucker ditch. See related cases in Missoula Light and Water Company and Missoula Public Service Company subgroups), 1901-1926 (Box-folder 151 / 5-7)
  - Employment Records
    - Payrolls [continued in Missoula Light and Water Company subgroup], 1901-1904 (Box-folder 151 / 8-11)
    - Payrolls: construction of new flume, 1902 (Box-folder 151 / 12-13)
    - Payrolls: construction of new flume, 1902 (Box-folder 152 / 1)
    - Payrolls: office [continued in Missoula Light and Water Company subgroup], 1898-1904 (Box-folder 152 / 2-5)
  - Financial Records
    - Cash book, 1901-1902 (Volume 323)
    - Financial statements [Oversize Box], 1901-1904 (Oversizebox 12)
    - General ledgers, 1886-1889 (Volume 324)
    - General ledgers [ledgers overlap in dates], 1889-1897 (Box-folder 152 / 6-7)
    - General ledgers, 1895-1904 (Box-folder 153 / 1-2)
    - Journal, 1890-1898 (Box-folder 153 / 3)
    - Journal (also includes other information), 1898-1900 (Box-folder 154 / 1)
    - Trial balances (1898-1904 volume labelled "Journal"), 1897-1904 (Box-folder 154 / 2-3)
  - Legal Documents
    - Miscellaneous (includes city franchise, contracts, leases, mortgages), 1889-1903 (Box-folder 154 / 4)
  - Organizational Records
    - Minutes of special meeting of board of directors, August 1901 (Box-folder 154 / 5)
  - Miscellany
    - Field books (re construction of pipeline from Rattlesnake Dam to Reservoir), circa 1902 (Box-folder 154 / 6-7)
- Missouri River Electric and Power Company
  - Historical Material
    - Historical information file, undated (Box-folder 155 / 1)
  - Financial Records
    - Cash book (Butte Electric and Power Company lease), 1912 (Volume 325)
    - Financial statements, 1912 (Box-folder 155 / 2)
    - General ledger, 1912 (Box-folder 155 / 3)
    - Voucher register (Butte Electric and Power Company lease), 1912 (Volume 326)
  - Legal Documents
    - Deed from George F. Shelton, special master for Missouri River Power Company in foreclosure, 1912 (Box-folder 155 / 4)
    - Lease agreements with Butte Electric and Power Company, 1912 (Box-folder 155 / 5)
    - Mortgage, 1912 (Box-folder 155 / 6)
  - Organizational Records
    - Miscellaneous (includes minutes, stock certificates, stockholder ledger, stockholder transfer journal), 1912 (Box-folder 155 / 7)
- Missouri River Power Company
  - Historical Material
    - Historical information file, undated (Box-folder 156 / 1)
  - General Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous (includes Helena Power Transmission Company; Samuel T. Hauser; William A. Clark), 1905-1906 (Box-folder 156 / 2)
    - Telegram (re flood damage), June 1908 (Box-folder 156 / 3)
    - Westinghouse Electric and Manufacturing Company [continued in Helena Power Transmission Company subgroup], 1903-1905 (Box-folder 156 / 4)
    - Westinghouse Machine Company [continued in Helena Power Transmission Company subgroup], 1905 (Box-folder 156 / 5)
  - Financial Records
    - Cash book, 1907-1909 (Volume 327)
    - Cash books, 1900-1907 (Box-folder 156 / 6-7)
    - Financial statements, 1900-1907 (Box-folder 156 / 8-10)
    - Financial statements, 1908-1909 (Box-folder 157 / 1-2)
    - General ledgers [3 sets of ledgers overlap and partially duplicate each other; difference unclear], 1900-1905 (Box-folder 157 / 3-4)
    - General ledgers, 1900-1906 (Box-folder 158 / 1-2)
    - General ledgers, 1901-1907 (Volume 328- 331)
    - General ledger index, 1900-1909 (Box-folder 158 / 3)
    - Journals, 1901-1909 (Volume 332- 333)
    - Journals [2 overlapping sets], 1900-1906 (Box-folder 158 / 4-5)
    - Journal, 1906-1908 (Box-folder 159 / 1)
    - Organizing committee journal, 1900-1901 (Box-folder 159 / 2)
    - Organizing committee ledger, 1900-1901 (Box-folder 159 / 3)
    - Trial balances, 1901-1904 (Box-folder 159 / 4)
    - Trial balances [Oversize Box], 1904-1906 (Oversizebox 12)
    - Voucher registers, 1903-1909 (Volume 334- 335)
    - Voucher register index, 1908- (Box-folder 159 / 5)
  - Legal Documents
    - Contracts: Anaconda Copper Mining Company subsidiaries, 1901-1910 (Box-folder 159 / 6)
    - Lease to Butte Electric and Power Company, 1912 (Box-folder 159 / 7)
    - Power contracts, 1896-1908 (Box-folder 159 / 8)
  - Organizational Records
    - Minutes [typescript copy], January 1905 (Box-folder 159 / 9)
    - Minute book index, 1900- (Box-folder 159 / 10)
    - Stockholder lists, 1902-1908 (Box-folder 159 / 11)
- Montana Power Company [1897]
  - Legal Documents
    - Contracts: Butte General Electric Company (re power from Big Hole River dam), 1897-1899 (Box-folder 159 / 12)
    - Contract: Forslund and Bertheau (re transmission lines from Big Hole River dam), 1897 (Box-folder 159 / 13)
  - Reports
    - Report by James L. Arnott (re Butte power plant and Big Hole River dam), 1899 (Box-folder 159 / 14)
- Montana Power Construction Company / Montana Power Company: Milwaukee Road Electrification
  - Interoffice Correspondence
    - Circular letters to foremen, timekeepers, clerks, etc., 1914-1916 (Box-folder 160 / 1-2)
    - Camp F, 1916 (Box-folder 160 / 3)
    - Camp G, 1916 (Box-folder 160 / 4)
    - Outfit train #6, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 160 / 5)
    - Outfit train #10, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 160 / 6-10)
  - General Correspondence
    - Chicago, Milwaukee and St. Paul Railway, 1914-1916 (Box-folder 160 / 11)
    - Florence Laundry Company, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 160 / 12)
    - A-W, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 160 / 13-15)
  - Employment Records
    - Payrolls: Camps A, B, F, H [Oversize Box], 1915-1916 (Oversizebox 13)
    - Payrolls: Camps and Outfit Trains 6, 8, 9, 10 [Oversize Box], 1915-1916 (Oversizebox 13)
  - Financial Records
    - Camp F Boarding House: summaries and inventories, 1916 (Box-folder 160 / 16)
    - Camp F Commissary: summaries and inventories, 1916 (Box-folder 160 / 17)
    - Camp F: construction reports [Oversize Box], 1916 (Oversizebox 14)
    - Camp F: copies of orders, 1916 (Box-folder 160 / 18)
    - Camp F: labor distribution, 1916 (Box-folder 160 / 19)
    - Camp F: progress reports, 1916 (Box-folder 160 / 20)
    - Camp G: construction reports [Oversize Box], 1916 (Oversizebox 14)
    - Camp G: miscellaneous, 1916 (Box-folder 160 / 21)
    - Camp #6 Boarding House: inventories, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 161 / 1)
    - Camp #6 Boarding House: summaries, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 161 / 2)
    - Camp #6 Commissary: inventories, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 161 / 3)
    - Camp #6 Commissary: summaries, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 161 / 4)
    - Camp #6: construction reports (transmission and trolley) [Oversize Box], 1915-1916 (Oversizebox 14)
    - Camp #6: requisitions, 1916 (Box-folder 161 / 5)
    - Camp #6: weekly progress reports, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 161 / 6)
    - Outfit Train #6: baggage reports, etc., 1915-1916 (Box-folder 161 / 7)
    - Outfit Train #6: copies of orders [scattered], 1915-1916 (Box-folder 161 / 8)
    - Outfit Train #6: labor distribution, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 161 / 9)
    - Outfit Train #6: orders on storekeeper, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 161 / 10)
    - Outfit Train #6: requisitions for supplies, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 161 / 11-12)
    - Outfit Train #6: work train delay reports, baggage, etc., 1916 (Box-folder 161 / 13)
    - Camp #8 Boarding House summary, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 162 / 1)
    - Camp #8 Commissary: summary, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 162 / 2)
    - Camp #8: construction reports (transmission and trolley) [Oversize Box], 1916 (Oversizebox 15)
    - Camp #8: progress reports, 1916 (Box-folder 162 / 3)
    - Camp #8: work train delays and baggage reports, 1916 (Box-folder 162 / 4)
    - Outfit Train #8: labor distribution summary, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 162 / 5-6)
    - Outfit Train #8: meals served, 1916 (Box-folder 162 / 7)
    - Outfit Train #8: record of cars in use, 1916 (Box-folder 162 / 8)
    - Camp #10 Boarding House: inventory, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 162 / 9)
    - Camp #10 Boarding House: summary, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 162 / 10)
    - Camp #10: construction reports (transmission) [Oversize Box], 1915-1916 (Oversizebox 15)
    - Camp #10: laundry bills, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 162 / 11)
    - Camp #10: progress reports, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 162 / 12)
    - Outfit Train #10 Commissary: inventories, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 162 / 13)
    - Outfit Train #10 Commissary: summaries, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 162 / 14)
    - Outfit Train #10: copies of orders (boarding house and commissary), 1915-1916 (Box-folder 163 / 1-4)
    - Outfit Train #10: equipment inventories, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 163 / 5)
    - Outfit Train #10: orders on storekeeper (electrification supplies), 1915-1916 (Box-folder 163 / 6-7)
    - Outfit Train #10: labor distribution, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 163 / 8)
    - Outfit Train #10: requisitions, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 163 / 9-11)
    - Outfit Train #14: progress reports, 1916 (Box-folder 163 / 12)
    - Chicago, Milwaukee and St. Paul Railway report of special equipment in service, 1916 (Box-folder 164 / 1)
    - Financial and operating statements, 1929-1931 (Volume 336)
    - General ledger, 1916-1931 (Box-folder 164 / 2)
    - Pay rate schedules, 1916 (Box-folder 164 / 3)
    - Petty ledger: purchases of groceries, 1915 (Box-folder 164 / 4)
    - Trial balance sheets [scattered], 1918-1928 (Box-folder 164 / 5)
    - Voucher registers, 1915-1917 (Volume 337- 338)
  - Legal Documents
    - Contract with St. Marie's Hospital Association, 1915 (Box-folder 164 / 6)
  - Organizational Records
    - Miscellaneous (includes articles of incorporation; bylaws; dissolution), 1916 (Box-folder 164 / 7)
  - Miscellany
    - Injury reports: B-T, 1916 (Box-folder 164 / 8)
    - Specifications, 1914-1916 (Box-folder 164 / 9)
- Montana Power Transmission Company
  - General Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous (correspondents include Roy Wells, Butte City Water Company, Max Hebgen), 1901-1904 (Box-folder 164 / 10)
  - Financial Records
    - Cash book, 1908-1909 (Volume 339)
    - Inventory of tools at lower dam and Wise River, undated (Box-folder 164 / 11)
  - Legal Documents
    - Mortgage, 1903 (Box-folder 164 / 12)
  - Organizational Records
    - Miscellaneous (includes certificate of incorporation, bylaws, annual reports of corporation), 1899-1904 (Box-folder 164 / 13)
  - Miscellany
    - Blueprint of truss for dam, undated (Box-folder 164 / 14)
    - Interruptions to power from Madison River, 1902 (Box-folder 164 / 15)
    - List of legal documents, other papers, etc., 1902 (Box-folder 164 / 16)
    - Power furnished by Butte Electric and Power Company and memoranda of power, 1900-1906 (Box-folder 164 / 17-18)
- Montana Reservoir and Irrigation Company
  - Financial Records
    - Analysis of interest and taxes during construction of Hebgen Dam, 1913-1915 (Box-folder 165 / 1)
    - Cash books, 1925-1934 (Volume 340- 341)
    - Financial and operating reports, 1929-1934 (Volume 342- 344)
    - General ledgers, 1914-1918 (Box-folder 165 / 2-7)
    - General ledgers, 1919-1925 (Box-folder 166 / 1-6)
    - General ledgers, 1926-1930 (Box-folder 167 / 1-5)
    - General ledgers, 1931-1934 (Box-folder 168 / 1-4)
    - General ledger: boarding house and commissary, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 168 / 5)
    - Report to Federal Trade Commission, 1928 (Box-folder 169 / 1)
    - Trial balances [Oversize Box], 1916-1928 (Oversizebox 15)
    - Voucher registers, 1914-1934 (Volume 345- 347)
  - Legal Documents
    - Contract: Union Power Company (re Hauser Dam), 1912 (Box-folder 169 / 2)
  - Organizational Records
    - Articles of incorporation, bylaws, increase in capital stock, 1906-1926 (Box-folder 169 / 3)
    - Minutes [scattered typescript copies], 1906-1913 (Box-folder 169 / 4)
    - Proxies, list of stockholders, etc., 1911-1913 (Box-folder 169 / 5)
    - Stockholder ledger/journal, 1906-1917 (Box-folder 169 / 6)
  - Reports
    - Report on proposed reservoir site between Great Falls and Cascade by Frank W. Bird., 1911 (Box-folder 169 / 7)
- Montana Water, Electric Power, and Mining Company
  - Financial Records
    - Power house record: Flint Falls [volume fire-damaged; Oversize Box], 1900-1901 (Oversizebox 170)
- National Realty Company
  - Historical Material
    - Historical information file, undated (Box-folder 171 / 1)
  - Financial Records
    - General ledgers, 1913-1926 (Box-folder 171 / 2-5)
    - Voucher register, 1922-1926 (Volume 348)
  - Organizational Records
    - Stock certificates, 1913-1926 (Box-folder 171 / 6)
- Northwestern Development Company
  - Financial Records
    - Cash book, 1912-1913 (Volume 349)
    - General ledger, 1912-1913 (Box-folder 172 / 1)
  - Legal Documents
    - Power contract: Iron Mountain Tunnel Company, 1913 (Box-folder 172 / 2)
  - Organizational Records
    - Bylaws, circa 1909 (Box-folder 172 / 3)
    - Stock certificates [blank], undated (Box-folder 172 / 4)
    - Stockholder ledger/journal, 1909-1911 (Box-folder 172 / 5)
- Parrot Silver And Copper Company
  - Financial Records
    - General ledger, 1897-1908 (Box-folder 173 / 1)
    - Journal (re property at Parrot, Montana, sold to Butte Electric and Power Company), 1897-1908 (Box-folder 173 / 2)
- People's Electric Light and Power Company
  - Financial Records
    - Cash book, 1903-1904 (Box-folder 173 / 3)
    - Meter locations, rates, etc., circa 1904 (Box-folder 173 / 4)
  - Organizational Records
    - Stock certificates, 1903-1908 (Box-folder 173 / 5)
- Phoenix Electric Company
  - Financial Records
    - Customer registers [variously titled], 1898-1919 (Volume 350- 356)
    - General ledgers, 1894-1907 (Volume 357- 359)
    - General ledger, 1909-1912 (Box-folder 174 / 1)
    - Heat register, 1907-1915 (Volume 360)
    - Journals, 1894-1909 (Volume 361- 362)
    - Voucher registers, 1898-1914 (Volume 363- 367)
  - Organizational Records
    - Articles of incorporation; Butte franchise; blank stock certificates, 1895-1896 (Box-folder 174 / 2)
    - Stockholder ledger, 1895-1921 (Box-folder 174 / 3)
- Phoenix Utility Company
  - Interoffice Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous, 1931 (Box-folder 175 / 1)
  - Employment Records
    - Payrolls: electric transmission line construction, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 175 / 2-6)
  - Financial Records
    - Agent's cash book, 1931-1934 (Volume 368)
    - Cash books, 1929-1932 (Volume 369- 370)
    - Daily field reports: equipment (includes Absarokee, Big Timber, Bozeman, Columbus, Livingston, Red Lodge, Roberts) [Oversize Box], 1931 (Oversizebox 176)
    - Daily field reports: labor (Job 1 Roberts, includes payroll) [Oversize Box], 1931 (Oversizebox 16)
    - Daily field reports: labor (Job 4 Dry Creek-Livingston) [Oversize Box], 1931 (Oversizebox 16)
    - Daily field reports: labor (Job 5A, Helena tap line) [Oversize Box], 1931 (Oversizebox 16)
    - Daily field reports: labor (Job 5A, Helena tap line) [Oversize Box], 1931 (Oversizebox 17)
    - Daily field reports: labor (Job 5A, Marias River Crossing) [Oversize Box], 1931 (Oversizebox 17)
    - Daily field reports: labor (Job 7, Helena Distribution System) [Oversize Box], 1931 (Oversizebox 18)
    - Daily field reports: labor (Livingston) [Oversize Box], 1931 (Oversizebox 19)
    - Flathead Hydro-Electric Development: bank books, 1930-1933 (Box-folder 177 / 1)
    - Flathead Hydro-Electric Development: cash book, 1930-1933 (Volume 371)
    - Flathead Hydro-Electric Development: check register, 1933-1934 (Volume 372)